## Tianhe Ren

rentianhe@idea.edu.cn

Github

Google Scholar

Homepage

I'm primarily interested in researching vision foundation models, object detection and segmentation, and multi-modal learning. I'm also passionate about open-source projects in AI community. The research work and open-source projects I'm involved in have garnered almost 20.0K stars on Github.

# **Employment History**

2022 - Now Computer Vision Engineer, International Digital Economy Academy (IDEA), Com-

puter Vision and Robotics Center.

2021 – 2022 Computer Vision Engineer, OneFlow, Vision Group.

## **Education**

2017 - 2021

Xiamen University, China.

Bachelor, GPA: 3.59/4.00

Major: School of Information Science and Engineering

# Research and Project Highlight

2023 - Now

■ Grounded-Segment-Anything: Marrying Grounding-DINO with Segment Anything & Stable Diffusion & Recognize Anything - Automatically Detect, Segment and Generate Anything.

Character: Project Lead & First Author

Github Stars: 12.8 K.

**Grounded-SAM** combines the strong open-set detector Grounding-DINO with promptable segmentation model (SAM) for detecting and segmenting arbitrary regions with users' textual inputs. **Grounded-SAM** is widely applied in various influenced work such as Florence-2, Emu-Edit, Task-Matrix and so on.

2022 - Now

**detrex**: detrex is a research platform for DETR-based object detection, segmentation, pose estimation and other visual recognition tasks.

Character: Project Lead & First Author

Github Stars: 1.7 K.

**detrex** is a deep-learning library built upon detectron2 and mainly focus on the transformer-based detection algorithms. **detrex** supports over 15 mainstream detection transformer algorithms and further boosts their performance from 0.2 AP to 1.1 AP by optimizing both model and training hyper-parameters.

2023 - Now

■ **Grounding-DINO**: Marrying DINO with Grounded Pre-Training for Open-Set Object Detection

Character: Main Contributor

Github Stars: 4.4 K.

**Grounding-DINO** combines the strong DINO detector with large-scale grounded pretraining which can detect any regions based on the user inputs.

## **Research Publications**

1. detrex: Benchmarking Detection Transformers

Tianhe Ren\*, Shilong Liu\*, Feng Li\*, Hao Zhang\*, Ailing Zeng, Jie Yang, Xingyu Liao, Ding Jia,

Hongyang Li, He Cao, Jianan Wang, Zhaoyang Zeng, Xianbiao Qi, Yuhui Yuan, Jianwei Yang, Lei Zhang. Tech report, May. 2023

### 2. Grounded SAM: Assembling Open-World Models for Diverse Visual Tasks

**Tianhe Ren**, Shilong Liu, Ailing Zeng, Jing Lin, Kunchang Li, He Cao, Jiayu Chen, Xinyu Huang, Yukang Chen, Feng Yan, Zhaoyang Zeng, Hao Zhang, Feng Li, Jie Yang, Hongyang Li, Qing Jiang, Lei Zhang

International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) Demo Track, 2023

# 3. Grounding DINO: Marrying DINO with Grounded Pre-Training for Open-Set Object Detection

Shilong Liu, Zhaoyang Zeng, **Tianhe Ren**, Feng Li, Hao Zhang, Jie Yang, Chunyuan Li, Jianwei Yang, Hang Su, Jun Zhu, Lei Zhang Tech report, May. 2023

## 4. Detection Transformer with Stable Matching

Shilong Liu\*, **Tianhe Ren\***, Jiayu Chen\*, Zhaoyang Zeng, Hao Zhang, Feng Li, Hongyang Li, Jun Huang, Hang Su, Jun Zhu, Lei Zhang

International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2023

## 5. A Strong and Reproducible Object Detector with Only Public Datasets

**Tianhe Ren**, Jianwei Yang, Shilong Liu, Ailing Zeng, Feng Li, Hao Zhang, Hongyang Li, Zhaoyang Zeng, Lei Zhang

Tech report, Apr. 2023

## 6. Cheap and Quick: Efficient Vision-Language Instruction Tuning for Large Language Models

Gen Luo, Yiyi Zhou, **Tianhe Ren**, Shengxin Chen, Xiaoshuai Sun, Rongrong Ji Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (**NeurIPS**), 2023

## 7. You Only Segment Once: Towards Real-Time Panoptic Segmentation

Jie Hu, Linyan Huang, **Tianhe Ren**, Shengchuan Zhang, Rongrong Ji, Liujuan Cao Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition **(CVPR)**, 2023

#### 8. Visual In-Context Prompting

Feng Li, Qing Jiang, Hao Zhang, **Tianhe Ren**, Shilong Liu, Xueyan Zou, Huaizhe Xu, Hongyang Li, Chunyuan Li, Jianwei Yang, Lei Zhang, Jianfeng Gao Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2024

### 9. T-Rex: Counting by Visual Prompting

Qing Jiang, Feng Li, **Tianhe Ren**, Shilong Liu, Zhaoyang Zeng, Kent Yu, Lei Zhang Tech report, Nov. 2023

#### 10. Exploring Vision Transformers as Diffusion Learners

He Cao, Jianan Wang, **Tianhe Ren**, Xianbiao Qi, Yihao Chen , Yuan Yao , Lei Zhang Tech report, Oct. 2022

#### 11. TRAR: Routing the Attention Spans in Transformers for Visual Question Answering

Yiyi Zhou, **Tianhe Ren**, Chaoyang Zhu , Xiaoshuai Sun, Jianzhuang Liu, Xinghao Ding, Mingliang Xu, Rongrong Ji

International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2021

# **Selected Projects**

2023 - Now

Grounded-Segment-Anything: Marrying Grounding-DINO with Segment Anything & Stable Diffusion & Recognize Anything - Automatically Detect, Segment and Generate Anything.

Github Stars: 12.8 K.

**Grounding-DINO**: Marrying DINO with Grounded Pre-Training for Open-Set Object Detection

Github Stars: 4.4 K.

2022 - 2023

**detrex**: detrex is a research platform for DETR-based object detection, segmentation, pose estimation and other visual recognition tasks.

Github Stars: 1.7 K.

2021 - 2022

■ LiBai: A Toolbox for Large-Scale Distributed Parallel Training based on the OneFlow Deep Learning Framework.

Github Stars: 371.

# **Professional Services**

Conference Reviewer

European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2024

## **Skills**

Programming

Python, LaTeX

**Programming Tools** 

PyTorch, PyTorch-Lightning, Scikit-Learn, Git, Linux